Finding Aid for the Fugitive and Agrarian Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Melvin E. Bradford
  - “A Modern Elegy: Ransom’s ‘Bells for John Whitesides’s Daughter’” reprinted from The Mississippi Quarterly, Vol. XXI, no. 1, Winter 1967 - 68 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Cleanth Brooks
  - Correspondence, outgoing and incoming (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - “ Alfred Edward Housman, 1859” Anniversary Lectures 1959, Lectures presented under The Auspices of the Gertrude Clarke Whittall Poetry and Literature Fund (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Notes on Understanding Poetry (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - “Tennessee Literary Festival” program, November 13 - 14, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Bibliography by James Grimshaw and articles (photocopies) (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - “Cleanth Brooks Remembered” by James Gollin in The American Scholar, Spring 1995 (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Wyatt Cooper
  - Review of Families: A Memoir and a Celebration in The Tennessean (Box 8, Folder 41)
- Louise Cowan
  - Newspaper articles and reviews The Fugitive Group: A Literary History (Box 8, Folder 42)
- James Dickey
  - “How Best to Live a Life?” in Toward the Year 2000: Perspectives on the Information Age, Bellsouth Corporation, 1986 Annual Report (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Fellowship of Soutbern Writers
  - Newspaper articles, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Ford Madox Ford
  - Reviews (Box 9, Folder 3)
- George Garrett
  - “The South” in American Libraries, January 1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Caroline Gordon
  - Letter to Edmund Wilson, May 17, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reviews (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - “Environmental and Psychological Formative Influences on Caroline Gordon” by Eleanor H. Beiswenger and “Penhally and Brackets: The Houses that Caroline Gordon Built” by Rebecca R. Butler in Border States: Journal of the Kentucky-Tennessee American Studies Association, No. 6, 1987 (Middle Tennessee State University) (Box 9, Folder 7)
- M. Thomas Inge
  - “The Fugitives and Agrarians: A Clarification” offprint from American Literature, Vol. 62,no.3, September 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - “Donald Davidson’s Notes for an Autobiography: The Early Years” in The Vanderbilt Tradition: Essays in Honor of Thomas Daniel Young, 1991 (photocopy signed by Inge) (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Randall Jarrell
  - Correspondence and Newspaper articles including obituaries; Oliver Max Gardner Award, North Carolina, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Memorial Poems by John Berryman, Robert Hase, Robert Lowell, Sister Bernetta Quinn, David Rigsbee, Gibbons Ruark, Robert Watson, John Wheatcroft, Lee Willoughby (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bibliographies: Margaret V. Kisslinger; Jeffrey Mayers; Library of Congress Contemporary Recordings, Text (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Mary Jarrell, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Robert Lowell
  - Review of Nihilist as Hero by Vereen Bell, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- David McDowell
  - “David McDowell: Forgotten Man of Letters” by Matthew Gwinn, c, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Arthur Mizener
  - “You Never Go Back to Sleep” typescript 1946 with correspondence John Crowe Ransom, Lionel Trilling (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Flannery O’Connor
  - Articles in The Southern Partisan, Vol. 4, no. 3, Summer, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Katherine Anne Porter
  - Articles and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Sister Bernetta Quinn
  - Correspondence and related items (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Louis D. Rubin, Jr
  - A Catalogue of the Fugitive Poets with an Essay by Louis D. Rubin, Jr .” Fugitives as Agrarians: The Impulse Behind I’ll Take My Stand” (Box 9, Folder 20)
- James Seay (1971 -74 Assistant Professor of English at Vanderbilt)
  - Poem, “Devices” in The Ohio Review, autographed page with invoice (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Jesse Stuart
  - Jesse Stuart Newsletter, Vol. 1, no. 1, no. 2, Murray, Kentucky, July - December 1960; January - June 1961 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Isabella Gardner Tate
  - Letters to Allen Tate, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Peter Taylor
  - “A Summons to Memphis” draft copy with corrections and annotations (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - “A Summons to Memphis” galley proof, Knopf (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Poetry from Agenda, 1976, Vol. 13, no. 4; Vol. 14, no. 1, Winter-Spring 1976 (also includes poetry by Eleanor Ross Taylor and Robert Lowell) (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Tennessee Day in St. Louis, Circle Players Program, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - “Shakespeare on the Beauteous Part of Man” by J.A. Bryant, Jr. January 1965 - inscribed to Taylor by the author (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Rosanna Warren
  - Postcard to Polly Hanson, May 16, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Richard Weaver
  - “The Tennessee Agrarians” in Shenandoah 3, Summer 1952, pp. 3 - 10 (photocopy) (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Eudora Welty
  - “Under the Spell of Eudora Welty” review by Robert Penn Warren in New York Times ‘Book Review, March 2, 1980 with other articles (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Kathryn Worth (Mrs. Walter Clyde Curry)
  - Correspondence with Ben Belitt, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 32)